I'm Dr. Joe Neely I practice with the Barton Oaks Dental Group.
I'm going to talk about the history of the toothbrush.
Need is definitely necessity is the mother of invention I believe is how that goes. And the toothbrush basically started as a stick that had been chewed on, and the end of the stick became softened and somewhat frayed.
And the stick was used to basically go across and scrape your teeth.
Early on there was also the use of bone, there are actually bone things that had been found by archaeologist that look to resemble toothpicks.
Because of the essence stuck in between your teeth you need something slender to slide in there and push it out.
Over time like any cleaning aid, people who were merchants found new ways to make them more efficient.
Or in the case of most modern toothbrushes more elaborate and interesting looking so that you can sell them.
But basically all a toothbrush is, is a cleaning tool that's of the appropriate size and shape to clean the object that you're trying to clean.
So truthfully the smaller the toothbrush usually, the better.